# Illana A. Stanley, Ph.D. – Fullstack JavaScript Developer

illana.stanley@gmail.com • (301) 655-9920 • San Francisco, CA

#### **SUMMARY**

Fullstack developer with expertise using JavaScript in both front end and back end development. Experienced in creating mobile-first, responsive web applications using React, Redux, jQuery, vanilla JavaScript, HTML5 and CSS3. Also experienced in developing RESTful APIs using Node, Express and MongoDB. Dedicated to continued learning and understanding the fundamentals. Possess advanced problem solving skills with a background in scientific research and medical education.

#### **SKILLS**

Advanced: JavaScript, ES6, React with Redux, Node.js, HTML5, CSS3, Git, GitHub

Proficient: Python, D3.js, TDD with Mocha/Chai and Jest/Enzyme, MongoDB, Webpack, Continuous

integration with Travis CI, Adobe Illustrator, Adobe Photoshop

**Expert:** Technical writing, project development lifecycle

## **RECENT PROJECTS**

Goal Keeper: Task management app designed to help users track progress of personal goals

• **GitHub:** https://github.com/iastanley/goal-keeper-client

My Acronym Dictionary: App for keeping a personal dictionary of acronyms used in various contexts

• **GitHub:** https://github.com/iastanley/my-acronym-dictionary-app

The Doc Locator: Location search client for doctors, integrated with Google Maps

• **GitHub:** https://github.com/iastanley/The-Doc-Locator

## **EDUCATION**

**Thinkful,** New York, NY – Training in fullstack web development **Harvard University, Division of Medical Sciences,** Boston, MA – Ph.D. in Cell Biology, November 2014 **Yale University**, New Haven, CT – B.S. in Molecular Biophysics and Biochemistry, May 2007

## **EXPERIENCE**

### Custom Learning Designs, Inc., Belmont, MA

Senior Medical Writer (August 2015 – April 2017)

- Generated technical content for educational deliverables used to train sales representatives in the pharmaceutical and biotech industry
- Engaged in team-based development of novel digital solutions for evolving client needs
- Executed effective project management, including adherence to strict deadlines, integration of client feedback and frequent iteration
- Worked in multidisciplinary team, consisting of writers, publishers, graphic designers and web developers, to create engaging and user-friendly training materials

#### Harvard Medical School and Dana-Farber Cancer Institute, Boston, MA

Graduate Student (2011 – 2014), Research Fellow (2014 – 2015)

- Received Ph.D. for basic science research on mitochondrial metabolism in B-cell lymphoma
- Analyzed and visualized complex data sets using various tools, including Excel, Adobe Illustrator, and GraphPad Prism